<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About My Website</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/index.html</link>
    <description>Welcome! Feel free to explore and take a tour around ~&#xA;This website is built with HUGO framework with Relearn theme by Mcshelby.&#xA;My name is Jeremy Chang and Piggy Botanist is my nickname. You can treat this website as my porfolio page, but also a place where I store content and experiments for myself.&#xA;Content and Accessing Resource If you are interested about me you can find more information here.&#xA;Content I store in this website will be focused on topics related to biology and computer science. You can also used the search tool beside to navigate to pages that you are interested in.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:41:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Computer_sciences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/computer_science/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:41:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/computer_science/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biologies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/biology/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 09:34:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/biology/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:49:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/index.html</guid>
      <description>Biography: I am a passionate bioinformatician who enjoys studying and designing complex computer algorithms and models to solve complicated biological problems that can provide innovative solution to challenges in medicine. The complex nature in biology and the power of computer science makes the field of computational biology a fascinating field of study for me.&#xA;I was formally trained as a feed microbiologist at the University of Guelph first with a Bachelor of Science - Honours (BScH) concentrated in biomedical science in 2022 then a Master’s degree (MSc) specialized in animal nutrition and microbiology in 2024. After my MSc degree I when on to pursuit my PhD degree at Mcgill University with a concentration in bioinformatics and computer science since 2024.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>